<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Tushar Sharma | Blog</title>
  <link href="https://randomwits.com/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://randomwits.com/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2013-09-13T18:38:58+05:30</updated>
  <id>https://ryanseys.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
    <email>tushar@randomwits.com</email>
  </author>
  
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/why-hacking-is-good</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/why-hacking-is-good"/>
    <title>Why hacking is good</title>
    <updated>2013-09-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;link href='../css/post.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a friend of mine asked if I could Hack. I asked him what he meant by hacking. Bemused at such a lame question he replied, &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t you know what hacking is?&amp;#8221;. On insisting he reluctantly explained, &amp;#8220;breaking into website or stealing passwords of Facebook, etc&amp;#8221;. I was crestfallen at the rampant misconception about hacking. &lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a friend of mine asked if I could Hack. I asked him what he meant by hacking. Bemused at such a lame question he replied, &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t you know what hacking is?&amp;#8221;. On insisting he reluctantly explained, &amp;#8220;breaking into website or stealing passwords of Facebook, etc&amp;#8221;. I was crestfallen at the rampant misconception about hacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='what_people_think_hacking_is'&gt;What people think hacking is&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often we read news of hackers breaking into websites siphoning millions of dollars. Such news not only create pervasive fear of hacking but also glorify such malicious activities. Media potrays hackers as precocious teenagers toying away with their hi-tech gadgets in their basement trying to circumvent securities. Their skills are often calibrated against the damage they can cause. Just google hacking and news of hackers getting convicted of breaching securities grabs the limelight. The most popular method used by such people involves defacing a website for &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism' target='_blank'&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt; which usually involves &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL_injection' target='_blank'&gt;SQL injecting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting' target='_blank'&gt;Cross Site Scripting&lt;/a&gt; (XSS) or &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack' target='_blank'&gt;Denal of service&lt;/a&gt; (DoS). None of the above techniques involves any sophisticated technical skills. Even if some of intrusion involved superior technical skills, it would not be hacking as it is against the hacker&amp;#8217;s ethics&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='what_hacking_really_is'&gt;What hacking really is&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacking is learning and building constructing things and nothing else. The concept of hacking emanated from MIT in 1960 where the term &amp;#8220;hacking&amp;#8221; resonated with creativity. Hacks were anything ingenious which may include any piece of code or even a clever prank. Hacker is used to denote a person who follows a spirit of playful cleverness and loves programming&lt;sup id='fnref:2'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:2' rel='footnote'&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. True hackers are those rare breed of people who are masterful programmers who beleive in freedom to access and share knowledge. As Eric Raymond aptly puts it, &amp;#8220;There is a community, a shared culture, of expert programmers and networking wizards that traces its history back through decades to the first time-sharing minicomputers and the earliest ARPAnet experiments. The members of this culture originated the term &amp;#8216;hacker&amp;#8217;. Hackers built the Internet. Hackers made the Unix operating system what it is today. Hackers run Usenet. Hackers make the World Wide Web work. If you are part of this culture, if you have contributed to it and other people in it know who you are and call you a hacker, you&amp;#8217;re a hacker&lt;sup id='fnref:3'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:3' rel='footnote'&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='what_is_the_difference'&gt;What is the difference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong /&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Type  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Known For&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/th&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ankit_Fadia' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/55/Ankitfadia2.jpg/200px-Ankitfadia2.jpg' style='height:150px;padding:15px 15px 15px 0px;max-width: 100px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Media Hacker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Ankit Fadia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt; Claimed that after the 9/11 attacks, &quot;American investigating agencies&quot; invited him to decode an encrypted message posted by Al-Qaeda. Thought he got much &lt;a href='http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/inside-account/article48684.ece' target='_blank'&gt;publicity&lt;/a&gt;, his claims are refuted &lt;a href='http://forbesindia.com/article/beyond-business/ankit-fadia-revealed/34793/0' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f7/Richard_Matthew_Stallman.jpeg/220px-Richard_Matthew_Stallman.jpeg' style='height:150px;padding:15px 15px 15px 0px;max-width: 100px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;True Hacker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Launched GNU Project, founding the Free Software Foundation, developing the GNU Compiler Collection and GNU Emacs, and writing the GNU General Public License &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id='conclusion'&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convictions of computer crimes, which began as early as 1983 with the case of 414&lt;sup id='fnref:4'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:4' rel='footnote'&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, caught the attention of the media. Rampant breach of security created panic among general public and intruders called themself &amp;#8216;hackers&amp;#8217;. These bunch of people, who writes malicious code, are nothing but crackers&lt;sup id='fnref:5'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:5' rel='footnote'&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Not only did they rob people of their money but also condemned such a beautiful word as &amp;#8216;hacker&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_ethic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:2'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_(term)#Programmer_subculture_of_hackers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:2' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:3'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html#whatis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:3' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:4'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_414s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:4' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:5'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.catb.org/jargon/html/C/cracker.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:5' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/huawei-usb-modem-in-debian</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/huawei-usb-modem-in-debian"/>
    <title>Huawei Usb Modem in Debian</title>
    <updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Debian claimed to be the Universal Operating System. Impressed by the stability &amp;amp; the community, I decided to switch to Debian. Earlier I used Fedora which handled all the hassles for me. Unlike Fedora, I had manually configure it to connect to the internet. But I soon realized it was not as difficult as it earlier seemed to be.&lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Debian claimed to be the Universal Operating System. Impressed by the stability &amp;amp; the community, I decided to switch to Debian. Earlier I used Fedora which handled all the hassles for me. Unlike Fedora, I had manually configure it to connect to the internet. But I soon realized it was not as difficult as it earlier seemed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be using &lt;code&gt;wvdial&lt;/code&gt; to configure the internet. It&amp;#8217;s likely that your system will have the package pre installed. Otherwise you can manyally download it from &lt;a href='http://packages.debian.org/squeeze/wvdial' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now connect the modem &amp;amp; run lsusb to see the modem connected to the usb &lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; lsusb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w4' src='/img/w4.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we see Huawie usb is visible as Huawei Wireless Data Modem. Now for detecting the modem run. &lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; wvdial /etc/wvdial.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w1' src='/img/w1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scans the usb port for modem. In my case the modem was detected in ttyUSB0. Now edit the wvdial.conf file. I am accustomed to use vi editor. But you can use any editor like gedit, nano, etc. Just replace vi with the name of your editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; vi  /etc/wvdial.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w3' src='/img/w3.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the semicolons &amp;amp; change the following values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Username: internet
Password: internet
Phone   : #777
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also add the following lines to wvdial.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Init3 = AT+CRM=1
Stupid Mode = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; wvdial&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bravo! It connects to the internet. Press &lt;b&gt;Ctrl + C&lt;/b&gt; anytime to disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You can also use the above method for other Linux distros. Some of the above commands require super user privelege. You can become super user simply be typing su.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/fear-of-walmart</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/fear-of-walmart"/>
    <title>Fear of Walmart</title>
    <updated>2012-03-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a ruckus the government agreed to roll back the proposed decision to increase FDI in retail sector. This could have paved way for the behemoth giants like Walmart to enter India. Indian Inc. was largely disappointed with the lack of much needed retail reform while the opposition parties including the local shopkeeper rejoiced over the fear of Walmart. &lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a ruckus the government agreed to roll back the proposed decision to increase FDI in retail sector. This could have paved way for the behemoth giants like Walmart to enter India. Indian Inc. was largely disappointed with the lack of much needed retail reform while the opposition parties including the local shopkeeper rejoiced over the fear of Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lack of education in economics convinced me of my inability to form an opinion on this matter. But as a concerned citizen , I tried to understand the repercussion of such an important law debated in the parliament. My first hurdle was to demystify FDI ( Foreign Direct Investment). FDI is way to control the investment of a foreign company. The investment may include purchase of land, building factories, employing people, etc. Usually FDI is restricted in countries to protect domestic companies against the might of the multi-national companies. But relaxing FDI organizes the sector, drives the economy, increases employment, etc. India liberalized most of its sectors after 1991 which also witnessed the boom of Indian IT sector. Currently FDI in retail sector is restricted below 51% forbidding companies like Walmart to pounce upon the Indian market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian acts like &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agricultural_Produce_Market_Committee'&gt;APMC&lt;/a&gt; have long forced farmers to only sell their products to the government mundis( market). Despite million starving in poverty, food grains across nation rots in the government godown(warehouse) thanks to the poor PDS. Unlike China, infrastructure in India is still poor. PDS( Public Distribution System) in India is also unorganized &amp;amp; less robust. Such shortcoming combined with other factors have left Indian farmers under the pangs of poverty. The rising inflation has forced RBI(Reserve Bank Of India) to continue to hike repo rates. This slowed the GDP( Gross Domestic Product) &amp;amp; devaluation of Indian ruppee against the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the much hyped Walmart would be a panacea for Indian consumers against the inflation? Entry of Walmart would usher the much needed reform in the retail sector. Food prices would fall as the Walmart would directly purchase food from the farmers thereby eliminating the middleman. India is perhaps the only developing country where Walmart is yet ink its presence. In contrast China has allowed 100% FDI in retail sector. Yet diluting FDI would be a arduous task for the central government walking a fine line between convincing the opposition &amp;amp; the local shopkeepers with a large chunk of the vote bank.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
