<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Tushar Sharma | Blog</title>
  <link href="https://randomwits.com/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://randomwits.com/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2013-10-20T01:17:04+05:30</updated>
  <id>https://ryanseys.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
    <email>tushar@randomwits.com</email>
  </author>
  
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/how-vim-saved-my-day</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/how-vim-saved-my-day"/>
    <title>How ViM Saved My Day</title>
    <updated>2013-10-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;link href='../css/post.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was just another day in Gurgaon. The hot scorching sun was parading the city. The inescapable life of riding with the autowalas is the common sight of this concrete jungle. Though I am a FOSS enthusiast, my first job landed me to just another India&amp;#8217;s IT company. I vividly remember the countless occasions when ViM saved my day. &lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags:  &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/vi' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;vi&amp;quot;'&gt;vi&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/vim' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;vim&amp;quot;'&gt;vim&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/editor' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;editor&amp;quot;'&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class='thumb' src='/../img/vim.png' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It was just another day in Gurgaon. The hot scorching sun was parading the city. The inescapable life of riding with the autowalas is the common sight of this concrete jungle.       Though I am a FOSS enthusiast, my first job landed me to just another India's IT company. I vividly remember the countless occasions when ViM saved my day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id='early_days'&gt;Early Days&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly received rudimentary tasks in early days of my work. I received one such task just few days after my joining. I was slouching on my chair when I heard this commanding voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“New joining”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, sir”, I replied looking around trying to find the source of the voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tall thin man with the air of authority stood glaring over my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come, I have a work for you”, he said and drew me to his cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He showed me a csv file. Unfortunately I can&amp;#8217;t post the original files but I&amp;#8217;ve tried to create resemblance of original file. See the picture 1 below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Picture1' src='/img/figure1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He began scrolling down the file. It took him more than two minutes to get to the middle of the file while my eyes remained glued to the screen counting the number of lines. At last when he reached the bottom, deducing my curiosity he said, “It has 2000 lines”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All you have to do”, he said, “is to pick each line of this CSV file and paste it to another text file with slight alteration”. He showed me another text file which resembled to Picture 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Picture2' src='/img/figure2.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each line should be similar to the other file”, he said pointing to Picture 2. Not only did I have to rearrange items of the line but also had to insert some extra text to match Picture 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you do it here”, I asked hoping if there was a trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have to do it manually”, he continued, “No other way”. Taking cognizance of my crestfallen face he said, “Don&amp;#8217;t worry. There&amp;#8217;s no hurry. You can take few days as you are new”, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With those words he left me with this task. Nothing peeves a programmer more than doing a monotonous repetitive work. But as every cloud has a sliver lining, similarly every problem too has a smarter solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='hello_vim'&gt;Hello ViM&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ViM stands for Vi Improved which is clone based on VI editor. If you&amp;#8217;ve never heard of vi, chances are you are still accustomed to the world of WYSIWYG editors like Notepad, etc. Well, those editors are great if you&amp;#8217;re daily tasks are to simply edit, copy, paste, search, etc but if you want to get you&amp;#8217;re hands dirty, vim is the panacea every programmer wants. Of course few other editors like emacs are equally powerful (or more&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;), but this post is about my romance with ViM (Sorry Emacs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally I would want to lay my hands on some Unix clone to get such task done. But my system was running legacy operating system, I did not have that luxury. Nevertheless most free&lt;sup id='fnref:2'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:2' rel='footnote'&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; softwares today easily run on non-Unix operating systems (like Windows). I fired internet explorer (to download firefox :) ) and downloaded a portable version of ViM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='smart_way'&gt;Smart Way&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ViM is a modal editor. Unlike other common editors, you can&amp;#8217;t start typing text in it straight away. ViM opens in command mode. To switch to insert mode, you have to press &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;. If you love typing and rarely use mouse (which most programmers do) then you&amp;#8217;ll love ViM. Navigation in ViM is by using classic &lt;code&gt;hjkl&lt;/code&gt; keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now its time to return to our problem i.e the file in Picture 1. I had to edit to look similar to file in Picture 2. To acomplish this task, I use a nifty feature of ViM called macros. Macros help to record my sequence of steps and play it again and again. In simple words, what I do for one line, I can repeat it for 1999 lines. These were sequence of steps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start recording the macro&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Jump to Fourth element of the file&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cut the whole line from this element upto the end&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Paste in the beginning of file&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Go to last element&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cut the last element&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Paste it before last two elements&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add extra text wherever required&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stop the macro&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Repeat the macro of 1999 lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To translate the above steps in ViM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;qa&lt;/code&gt; to start the macro and save it in register a&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; to search for comma. Press &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; 2 times to reach fourth element&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; to cut the line from fourth element to end&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; to go to begining of file. Press &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; to paste.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; to reach last element.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt; to cut the last element&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; to reverse search comma and press &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;. Press &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; to paste.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Copy paste extra text where required. Press &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; to enter insert mode and to paste press &lt;code&gt;SHIFT&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;CTRL&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;V&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; to jump off the line and press &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; to stop the macro&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;1999@a&lt;/code&gt; to repeat macro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can reduce the number of steps by a more elegant solution. But this alone helped me solve my task. See my resulted file in Picture 3 below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Picture3' src='/img/figure3.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='even_more_smart_way'&gt;Even More Smart Way&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you have to repeat this task again and again. It&amp;#8217;s cumbersome to write the same macro again and again after you switch off your machine. There&amp;#8217;s a way to store macro so that you don&amp;#8217;t need to remember them. First copy the value of your macro. To see your macro&amp;#8217;s value type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:anew

:&amp;quot;ap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And copy paste this value of macro in your &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;let @a = &amp;#39;MACRO_VALUE&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just replace MACRO_VALUE with the value of your own macro. Here&amp;#8217;s value of my own macro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;0/,^Mnnlv$hd0i ^[p^[0^[lu^[uuuuuuuuuuuuuuu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Voila! Your Macro is saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='conclusion'&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ViM is a wonderful editor if only you get to know it. The following task took me less than 15 minutes to complete. Of course less than 15 minutes feat dazzled my supervisor but more than the approval it&amp;#8217;s the satisfaction that comes from solving problems smartly. So what&amp;#8217;s your story? Have ViM ever saved your day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a famous editor war between VI and Emacs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:2'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free means as if freedom not gratis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:2' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/why-hacking-is-good</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/why-hacking-is-good"/>
    <title>Why hacking is good</title>
    <updated>2013-09-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;link href='../css/post.css' rel='stylesheet' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a friend of mine asked if I could Hack. I asked him what he meant by hacking. Bemused at such a lame question he replied, &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t you know what hacking is?&amp;#8221;. On insisting he reluctantly explained, &amp;#8220;breaking into website or stealing passwords of Facebook, etc&amp;#8221;. I was crestfallen at the rampant misconception about hacking. &lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags:  &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/hacking' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;hacking&amp;quot;'&gt;hacking&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/hackers' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot;'&gt;hackers&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/code' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;code&amp;quot;'&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class='thumb' src='/../img/glider.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a friend of mine asked if I could Hack. I asked him what he meant by hacking. Bemused at such a lame question he replied, &quot;Don't you know what hacking is?&quot;. On insisting he reluctantly explained, &quot;breaking into website or stealing passwords of Facebook, etc&quot;. I was crestfallen at the rampant misconception about hacking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id='what_people_think_hacking_is'&gt;What people think hacking is&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often we read news of hackers breaking into websites siphoning millions of dollars. Such news not only create pervasive fear of hacking but also glorify such malicious activities. Media potrays hackers as precocious teenagers toying away with their hi-tech gadgets in their basement trying to circumvent securities. Their skills are often calibrated against the damage they can cause. Just google hacking and news of hackers getting convicted of breaching securities grabs the limelight. The most popular method used by such people involves defacing a website for &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism' target='_blank'&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt; which usually involves &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL_injection' target='_blank'&gt;SQL injecting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting' target='_blank'&gt;Cross Site Scripting&lt;/a&gt; (XSS) or &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack' target='_blank'&gt;Denal of service&lt;/a&gt; (DoS). None of the above techniques involves any sophisticated technical skills. Even if some of intrusion involved superior technical skills, it would not be hacking as it is against the hacker&amp;#8217;s ethics&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='what_hacking_really_is'&gt;What hacking really is&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacking is learning and building constructing things and nothing else. The concept of hacking emanated from MIT in 1960 where the term &amp;#8220;hacking&amp;#8221; resonated with creativity. Hacks were anything ingenious which may include any piece of code or even a clever prank. Hacker is used to denote a person who follows a spirit of playful cleverness and loves programming&lt;sup id='fnref:2'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:2' rel='footnote'&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. True hackers are those rare breed of people who are masterful programmers who beleive in freedom to access and share knowledge. As Eric Raymond aptly puts it, &amp;#8220;There is a community, a shared culture, of expert programmers and networking wizards that traces its history back through decades to the first time-sharing minicomputers and the earliest ARPAnet experiments. The members of this culture originated the term &amp;#8216;hacker&amp;#8217;. Hackers built the Internet. Hackers made the Unix operating system what it is today. Hackers run Usenet. Hackers make the World Wide Web work. If you are part of this culture, if you have contributed to it and other people in it know who you are and call you a hacker, you&amp;#8217;re a hacker&lt;sup id='fnref:3'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:3' rel='footnote'&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='what_is_the_difference'&gt;What is the difference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong /&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Type  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align='center'&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Known For&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/th&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ankit_Fadia' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/55/Ankitfadia2.jpg/200px-Ankitfadia2.jpg' style='height:150px;padding:15px 15px 15px 0px;max-width: 100px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Media Hacker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Ankit Fadia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt; Claimed that after the 9/11 attacks, &quot;American investigating agencies&quot; invited him to decode an encrypted message posted by Al-Qaeda. Thought he got much &lt;a href='http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/inside-account/article48684.ece' target='_blank'&gt;publicity&lt;/a&gt;, his claims are refuted &lt;a href='http://forbesindia.com/article/beyond-business/ankit-fadia-revealed/34793/0' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='http://static.fsf.org/fsforg/img/rms-web.jpg' style='height:150px;padding:15px 15px 15px 0px;max-width: 100px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;True Hacker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align='center'&gt;Launched GNU Project, founding the Free Software Foundation, developing the GNU Compiler Collection and GNU Emacs, and writing the GNU General Public License &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id='conclusion'&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convictions of computer crimes, which began as early as 1983 with the case of 414&lt;sup id='fnref:4'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:4' rel='footnote'&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, caught the attention of the media. Rampant breach of security created panic among general public and intruders called themself &amp;#8216;hackers&amp;#8217;. These bunch of people, who writes malicious code, are nothing but crackers&lt;sup id='fnref:5'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:5' rel='footnote'&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Not only did they rob people of their money but also condemned such a beautiful word as &amp;#8216;hacker&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_ethic' target='_blank'&gt;Hacker ethic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:2'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_(term)#Programmer_subculture_of_hackers' target='_blank'&gt;Hacker_(term)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href='#fnref:2' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:3'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html#whatis' target='_blank'&gt;How to be a hacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href='#fnref:3' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:4'&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_414s' target='_blank'&gt;414&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href='#fnref:4' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id='fn:5'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.catb.org/jargon/html/C/cracker.html' target='_blank'&gt;Jargon file - Cracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href='#fnref:5' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/huawei-usb-modem-in-debian</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/huawei-usb-modem-in-debian"/>
    <title>Huawei Usb Modem in Debian</title>
    <updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Debian claimed to be the Universal Operating System. Impressed by the stability and the community, I decided to switch to Debian. Earlier I used Fedora which handled all the hassles for me. Unlike Fedora, I had manually configure it to connect to the internet. But I soon realized it was not as difficult as it earlier seemed to be.&lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags:  &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/debian' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;debian&amp;quot;'&gt;debian&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/huawei' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;huawei&amp;quot;'&gt;huawei&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/usb' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;usb&amp;quot;'&gt;usb&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/modem' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;modem&amp;quot;'&gt;modem&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/code' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;code&amp;quot;'&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class='thumb' src='/../img/debian.jpg' /&gt;
The Debian claimed to be the Universal Operating System. Impressed by the stability and the community, I decided to switch to Debian. Earlier I used Fedora which handled all the hassles for me. Unlike Fedora, I had manually configure it to connect to the internet. But I soon realized it was not as difficult as it earlier seemed to be.
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be using &lt;code&gt;wvdial&lt;/code&gt; to configure the internet. It&amp;#8217;s likely that your system will have the package pre installed. Otherwise you can manyally download it from &lt;a href='http://packages.debian.org/squeeze/wvdial' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now connect the modem and run lsusb to see the modem connected to the usb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ lusub&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w4' src='/img/w4.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we see Huawie usb is visible as Huawei Wireless Data Modem. Become a super user by typing &lt;code&gt;sudo su&lt;/code&gt;. Now for detecting the modem run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# wvdial /etc/wvdial.conf &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w1' src='/img/w1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scans the usb port for modem. In my case the modem was detected in ttyUSB0. Now edit the wvdial.conf file. I am accustomed to use vi editor. But you can use any editor like gedit, nano, etc. Just replace vi with the name of your editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# vi /etc/wvdial.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='w3' src='/img/w3.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the semicolons &amp;amp; change the following values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Username: internet
Password: internet
Phone   : #777&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also add the following lines to wvdial.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Init3 = AT+CRM=1
Stupid Mode = 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# wvdial&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bravo! It connects to the internet. Press &lt;b&gt;Ctrl + C&lt;/b&gt; anytime to disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://randomwits.com/blog/fear-of-walmart</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://randomwits.com/blog/fear-of-walmart"/>
    <title>Fear of Walmart</title>
    <updated>2012-03-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Tushar Sharma</name>
      <uri>https://randomwits.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a ruckus the government agreed to roll back the proposed decision to increase FDI in retail sector. This could have paved way for the behemoth giants like Walmart to enter India. Indian Inc. was largely disappointed with the lack of much needed retail reform while the opposition parties including the local shopkeeper rejoiced over the fear of Walmart. &lt;!-- truncate_here --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags:  &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/Walmart' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;Walmart&amp;quot;'&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a class='mytag' href='/tag/FDI' title='View posts tagged with &amp;quot;FDI&amp;quot;'&gt;FDI&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class='thumb' src='/../img/walmart.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a ruckus the government agreed to roll back the proposed decision to increase FDI in retail sector. This could have paved way for the behemoth giants like Walmart to enter India. Indian Inc. was largely disappointed with the lack of much needed retail reform while the opposition parties including the local shopkeeper rejoiced over the fear of Walmart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lack of education in economics convinced me of my inability to form an opinion on this matter. But as a concerned citizen , I tried to understand the repercussion of such an important law debated in the parliament. My first hurdle was to demystify FDI ( Foreign Direct Investment). FDI is way to control the investment of a foreign company. The investment may include purchase of land, building factories, employing people, etc. Usually FDI is restricted in countries to protect domestic companies against the might of the multi-national companies. But relaxing FDI organizes the sector, drives the economy, increases employment, etc. India liberalized most of its sectors after 1991 which also witnessed the boom of Indian IT sector. Currently FDI in retail sector is restricted below 51% forbidding companies like Walmart to pounce upon the Indian market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian acts like &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agricultural_Produce_Market_Committee'&gt;APMC&lt;/a&gt; have long forced farmers to only sell their products to the government mundis( market). Despite million starving in poverty, food grains across nation rots in the government godown(warehouse) thanks to the poor PDS. Unlike China, infrastructure in India is still poor. PDS( Public Distribution System) in India is also unorganized and less robust. Such shortcoming combined with other factors have left Indian farmers under the pangs of poverty. The rising inflation has forced RBI(Reserve Bank Of India) to continue to hike repo rates. This slowed the GDP( Gross Domestic Product) and devaluation of Indian ruppee against the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the much hyped Walmart would be a panacea for Indian consumers against the inflation? Entry of Walmart would usher the much needed reform in the retail sector. Food prices would fall as the Walmart would directly purchase food from the farmers thereby eliminating the middleman. India is perhaps the only developing country where Walmart is yet ink its presence. In contrast China has allowed 100% FDI in retail sector. Yet diluting FDI would be a arduous task for the central government walking a fine line between convincing the opposition and the local shopkeepers with a large chunk of the vote bank.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
